

+91-9944998621

SIIRAT@GMAIL.COM



1103, CB-3, SUPERTECH CAPETOWN, NOIDA – 201304

EDUCATION

M.TECH, SASTRA 2007-12

CGPA - 9.17 out of 10

SKILLS

CSS3

JavaScript (ES6)

React.JS

Angular.JS

HTML 5

HOBBIES

- Photography
- · Table Tennis

SERAT FATIMA RIZVI

USER INTERFACE DEVELOPER | REACT.JS, ANGULAR.JS

SAPIENT TECHNOLOGIES

LinkedIn Profile: https://www.linkedin.com/in/serat-fatima-rizvi-3a405410/

Actively looking for a Sr. UI Developer/Team Lead role in a global corporation

PROFILE SUMMARY

UI Developer with 5+ years of experience in cross browser responsive platform in organizations like TCS, Trimble Navigations and Sapient Technologies. During my tenure in these organizations, I have gained expertise in the following front end technologies: JavaScript ES5 and ES6, Angular.JS, React.JS with MobX, Backbone with Marionette.JS, jQuery, Bootstrap, HTML5, CSS3, SASS, Less, Karma, Jasmine, Webpack, Require.JS, Node.JS. Experienced in working in distributed Agile environment.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Sapient Technologies July 2016 - Present

Interactive UI Developer Large US based Bank

- Developed the cross browser web based banking platform for customers to perform retail banking operations.
- Transitioned the existing application from Marionette.JS to React.JS and developed new functionalities in the application using React.JS

Trimble Navigations Sep 2014 - June 2016

Software Engineer

- Developed and supported the application for tracking heavy construction devices. Worked on Modular JavaScript patterns.
- Used HTML5/CSS3, Bootstrap for the interface development. Integrated maps functionality using Google Map and ALK Map APIs
- Developed Kanban board tool using HTML5, CSS3 and Angular JS Framework.

Tata Consultancy Services Aug 2012 - Sept 2014

Systems Engineer

- Front end development of the cross-browser responsive Platform consisting of multiple web applications using single page approach with HTML5, CSS3 and Angular JS.
- Gained Object Oriented JavaScript development experience. Used Google Map APIs integration, Adobe Photoshop, AJAX. Optimized the application to make it work in Mozilla. Chrome, IE8+ with equivalent user experience.